Privacy Policy
==============

This Policy may be amended as new features, technology or legal requirements arise so please check back from time to time. We’ll notify you if any significant changes are made.

###### Cookies

Spamdrain uses cookies to assist with functions such as user identification, remembering user site preferences, understanding how users interact with the website and tracking the effectiveness of marketing efforts. Spamdrains functional cookies, meaning cookies that are necessary to enable the website to work as intended (e.g. cookies that recognize the user being logged in), do not track your browsing activitity on non-Spamdrain sites.

When visiting our website for the first time, we will ask if you agree to us placing cookies from third parties on your computer. Spamdrain utilizes technologies from Google Analytics and Zendesk to analyze and improve our website and marketing, and to provide anonymous demographic user data, but we will only place such third party cookies on your computer if you agree to us doing so. To learn more about how Google Analytics uses your data when visiting our website, visit [policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). To learn more about how Zendesk uses your data when visiting our website, visit [support.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360022367393-Zendesk-in-product-cookie-policy](https://support.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360022367393-Zendesk-in-product-cookie-policy).

###### What personal data does Spamdrain collect and receive?

Spamdrain is an email filtering service that continually monitors your email inbox and removes unwanted spam and viruses. In order to provide these Services, Spamdrain will receive a copy of your incoming emails and store that copy for 60 days to ensure that none of your important emails get lost. This means that Spamdrain may receive many kinds of personal information contained in your emails. We also collect the following types of information:

* Subscriber information. In order to open your account and process payments we collect your email address and general payment information.
* Email Password. To enable Spamdrain we need to gain access to your email account and to enable such access.
* Log Data. Spamdrain is a learning algorithm and we therefore collect data to help the service better understand which emails are to be filtered and which are not. This information helps us provide you with a better service and to identify ways to make the service more useful to you.
* Location Data. We determine IP address that users sign up from in order to establish the country. Depending on country the currency is set while placing an order.

In addition to this, we may also need to process your personal data in order to provide troubleshooting and customer support. Regarding our access to your emails, we limit the use of such data so that no one at Spamdrain shall access it unless you give us permission or access is necessary to comply with a legal obligation. In providing customer support we may need to access the data you have stored in Spamdrain, for instance if the support matter regards retrieving a backup of deleted or lost emails. We will in such a case ask for your permission to access your data.

We may also occasionally use your contact information for direct marketing purposes or to announce new products and features, share tips and provide additional information.

Our legal basis for processing your data is fulfillment of the agreement you have with us, wherein we provide you with the Spamdrain services. The use of your contact information for direct marketing purposes is based on our legitimate interest of marketing our products. You may object to such marketing as specified below.

###### How does Spamdrain share your personal data?

When Spamdrain shares your data with a third party, it is always to achieve the same purpose for which the data was originally collected and only the minimum information necessary will be shared. Spamdrain does not share your information with any third parties for their own advertising purposes.

We share your information with Service Providers who process data on our behalf, including computing- and storage services, customer support providers and payment processors. We require these Service Providers to agree to strict data protection requirements in keeping with data protection regulations.

We make an effort to ensure that your personal data is not unnecessarily transferred to countries outside of the EEA. We may however from time to time need to employ Service Providers where such transfers will be necessary, such as our customer support and application development provider who are located in the Ukraine. If you are a resident of the EEA, please note that we will at all times make sure that such transfers are subject to adequate safeguards in the form of standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission.

###### How can you manage your personal data?

You may at any time request confirmation from us on whether we store any of your personal data. If that is the case, you may also request copies of such data.

You can manage the personal data stored by Spamdrain by using our app. However, if you prefer, you can contact us and request that we correct, update or delete your personal information. We may ask for proof of account ownership before fulfilling your request.

In addition you may request a restriction on our processing of your personal data; for instance if you’ve requested that we correct some of your personal information, you may also request that we restrict the processing of that data while your request is being handled. Some of your information may also be used for direct marketing purposes by Spamdrain, based on our legitimate interests. You may object to such processing of your personal data.

Requests can be sent to [support@spamdrain.com](mailto:support@spamdrain.com). Spamdrain will comply with all requests to the extent required by applicable data protection laws.

###### What happens if you want to stop using Spamdrain?

You can delete your data at any time while logged in to your account, and you can stop using Spamdrain at any time.

If you delete your data, Spamdrain back-up systems may retain residual copies of your deleted data for up to 1 year due to the nature of these systems. If you let your subscription lapse or choose to cancel your subscription, Spamdrain will continue to store a copy of your data for 90 days after which your data will be deleted unless your subscription is renewed within that time. As regards copies of your emails, these copies are always deleted 60 days after they was initially received, regardless whether the subscription is in effect of has been terminated. If you wish for the data to be deleted at an earlier time, you may notify us and we will comply within 30 days of such notification.

Furthermore, your data is portable and can be exported from Spamdrain at any time. To export your data, please send an export request to [support@spamdrain.com](mailto:support@spamdrain.com).

###### How can I contact Spamdrain?

Spamdrain welcomes your feedback regarding this Privacy Policy. If you have questions, comments or concerns about this Policy, please contact us by email at [support@spamdrain.com](mailto:support@spamdrain.com) or postal mail at:

Spamdrain AB  
Box 53200  
SE-400 15 Gothenburg
